So now we are going to program Mifare Classic one cards.
And first we will see how to program a value blocks sorry, the data blocks.
Then later we will see how to program sector trailers and value blocks as well.
So before programming mifare classic cards, make sure this memory structure is open on your screen
so it will help you a lot in programming and it will help you a lot while checking out the addresses
and sector trailers as well.
All right.
So let's just get started on it.
Let me make it a little zoom and let's just minimize it.
So as I told you, that 1 to 2 comes with its own SDK.
So make sure you get that SDK from wherever you purchase this 1 to 2.
And this is the SDK over here.
So this is the SDK I have got from my own cellar.
So make sure you get this SDK from your cellar as well.
So all you have to do is you just have to do a few clicks and this tool will install automatically.
It's not that hard, so I'm not going to show you how to install this tool, but you can install this
tool very easily.
It's just few clicks right After installing this tool on Windows 10, I have to also install the drivers
of ACR one two, two so you can get the drivers very easily.
This is the link through which you can get the drivers.
I will provide this link in the resources file as well.
So I have to download this MSI installer for PC.
SC Driver.
It's around five MB, so you can download it.
And for Windows 10, I have to download this driver after installing the SDK so you can download this
driver.
And let's just start the tool.
So over here there is a folder ACR one, two, two.
So let me click on it.
And there are basically two tools which comes with this SDK.
The first one is ACR one, two, two tool, and the other one is easy key.
So we are going to see Easy Key later in our video series.
But for now, let's just click on ACR one, two, two tool.
Right.
So let's just go through the screen first.
So this is the log screen.
You will get all the details like if the card is updated successfully or there are some errors, you
will get those errors instantly on log screen over here.
Right?
So let's just first make a connection with our ACR 1 to 2 device.
So to make a connection, you can make a connection from here as well.
Reader commands so you can make a new connection and you will get ACR one, two, two.
Over here in the readers, if you have multiple readers, you will get all the readers over here.
Let me cancel out it.
And you can also make connection from this instant button over here.
So let's just click on it and you can make a connection from here as well, right?
So on the small screen over here, you can see that right now, the, uh, the ACR one, two, two is
connected, but showing the red led, right?
So it's showing the red led because we haven't placed any card on it.
So let's just first place a mifare classic one card.
So this is one card you can see.
Well, as soon as I placed this card, the lid goes on green.
So let's just.
Place this card.
So the Led will be green and let's just do our connection now.
So for 1 to 2 you is connected.
So let's just click on Readers command and over here you can see get data.
So get data will print the Uid of the card.
So let's just.
Do get data.
And over here you can see the Uuid of the card.
Right.
So this is the of this card and each card has a different Uid.
So let me show you another card which has a different uid.
So let me remove this card.
And the lady will again go on, read and let's just do a close connection.
And we will place another card.
This is a different card.
So let's just do.
Reconnect.
And again, do get data.
So over here you can see the Uid is different.
It's easy to see A6919 and over here it's E to d e.
0519.
So you can see clearly the uuids are different on each card.
So let's just clear out our screen so or we can keep the Uuid as well.
Let me show you one more thing.
So over here in Raiders Command, there is another option, which is get HDR, right?
So let's just click on it.
This will show you multiple options like load authentication, keys, authenticate, read, write,
read, value, write value, increment, decrement and copy.
We are going to see all these options in very detail in this video.
So let's just first use load authentication.
Keys.
And over here you can see load authentication, key menu.
It is a pop up and over here you can see the command.
Sorry, the keys f f, f, f, f, f, f, f, f f.
Right.
So as I told you in my previous video animation card comes with transport configuration.
Any new card you purchase will always come with a transport configuration.
And in transport configuration all the keys are f, f, f, f, f, f, f, f, f, f.
Right.
So this is the key.
You have to basically, if you have changed the keys from anywhere, any other software, you have to
provide the correct key over here.
But right now the card is on transport configuration.
So it is loading the default keys right now.
Right?
So but if you have another key, you have to provide the key over here, right?
So make sure you provide the correct key over here.
So right now the my card is on transport configuration, so I don't need to change the keys, so I'll
just do.
Okay.
Right.
So load authentication.
Authentication key success.
Right.
So this is the message we are getting on log.
A screen.
And now let's just authenticate our block.
So we will authenticate with key type A because we have already loaded our key and we have to provide
the block number.
So let's just load a authenticate block zero first.
And authentication success.
That means our block is authenticated successfully.
Now let's just read this block.
So we are going to read this block with the read command and read binary block.
And we have to provide the block number, which is zero, which is already written over here.
So we don't need to change anything over here.
And then we have to provide the number of bytes to read.
We will read all the 16 bytes and then we will read in hexadecimal format and we can also read it in
Ascii format as well.
We will see later how to read as key as well.
Right now we will read the block in hexadecimal, so let's just click on it.
And over here you can see the hex mode and the 16 bytes of data in block zero.
Right.
So this is the 16 bytes of data in block zero.
So over here you can notice the first four bytes are exactly identical to the Uid.
Right.
So as I told you before, the Block zero is the manufacturer's block, and the first four bytes represent
the Uid of any card.
Right.
So you can compare the Uid as well.
Where is the.
Let me check it out.
So let's just load the kids one more time and we will compare it as well.
So here is the UI, right?
And you can compare the UI with the first four blocks of block zero.
It's exactly identical.
So you can see this.
So Block zero is manufacturers.
Block Right Now, let's just authenticate block one because we are on a transport transport configuration.
We don't need to change the keys because keys are similar.
So we will just do authenticate.
Block Zero.
Authentication success.
And let's just read Block zero.
We are going to read blog zero in hexadecimal.
And you can see hex mode and all the zeros over here.
So there is no data on block zero or the data is 000.
You can say anything.
And now let's just authenticate block two as well.
Now let's just read block two.
Block two is also 000.
Right now let's just authenticate block three.
And if you remember from our memory structure, Block three in each sector is a sector trailer, and
block three contains the key A key B and excess bits of any sector, right?
So block three in sector Zero is the sector trailer.
So we will authenticate this block three first.
And let's just read the block three in the hexadecimal.
So over here you can see we have read the Block three successfully as well.
But you can notice we are not able to read Key A.
So as I told you before, Key A is never readable.
In any case, whatever the access bit condition is, you are not able to read key A technically, but
in our later videos when we will see how to crack these cards and how to find vulnerabilities in this
card, we will also see how to read this card through another tool, which is Prox three.
We will see this in later videos, so don't worry.
But till now, officially you cannot read key A so you are not able to read key A You can read key B
because we are on a transport configuration and in transport configuration we can easily read key B
and all the access bits as well.
Similarly, let's just authenticate another block tractor trailer block.
So.
Let's just.
Authenticate.
Block 11 over here.
Uh, there is a reason.
There is a reason.
I'm authenticating block 11 to show you one condition.
So let's just authenticate block 11 first.
Because over here you can see block 11 is sector trailer, right?
So technically, we should get all the keys.
Sorry.
The key B and the access bits and key A should be hidden.
Right.
When we will do authenticate block 11.
So let's just authenticate.
Block 11.
And over here you can see authentication success.
Now let's just read block level.
So as you can see in hex mode, Block 11 is showing all the zeros.
Now, why is that?
It is because over here in authentication and this complete tool work on hexadecimal format, not in
decimal.
Over here you can see all the addresses in decimal format in our memory structure.
But this tool reads data in hexadecimal format.
You have to remember this key point, right?
Let me repeat this one more time.
So this tool read all the data in hexadecimal format.
So 11 in hex hexadecimal is some other number, and in decimal it's a different number.
So let's just convert this 11 into hexadecimal.
So there are multiple tools available to convert this.
So let's just do.
Hexa to decimal to hexa.
So our number is 11.
In decimal, let's just convert this number.
So in hexadecimal 11 is equal to b.
Right.
And ten is equal to a.
As you can see.
So.
11 is equal to B.
As you can see.
So let's just type B.
And see if we can get the sector trailer or not.
So we have authenticated block B, which is in decimal block 11.
And let's just read.
We will read Block B and we are successfully able to read Sector trailer of Block sector three, I suppose.
Yeah.
Uh, or sector two.
Sorry.
So 11 is in sector two.
As you can see it over here in memory structure.
So 11 is in Sector two.
We are easily able to read through hexadecimal and let's just try to read authentic first authenticate.
Block A as well.
And let's just read block A.
So block A is 000.
So block A is ten and 11 is equal to B in hexadecimal.
So you have to remember this key point.
So now we are able to read data.
Let's just write some data as well.
So to write data, it's not that difficult.
It's just you clicks through this SDK, so you have to first authenticate the block in which you have
to write data.
Let's just.
Authenticate block for first.
Which is in sector one.
Uh, and.
Let's just write block number four.
And string authentication success.
Now let's just read.
So showing all the zeros and we will write some data.
So we can write data in hexadecimal as well as in Ascii.
So to write data in SRC is quite simple and easy, so we will use SRC format.
And make sure you write all the 16 bytes of data.
Right.
So hello world is equal to 16 bytes, so let's just click.
Okay.
So write binary block success.
Now let's just read block for.
First we will read in hexadecimal.
So this is the hexadecimal of Ascii characters which we have written.
So no matter if you write in Ascii format or in hexadecimal format, the data will be written in hexadecimal
format in Mifare cards.
So let's just read the data as well.
In Ascii format.
So you can see.
Hello world.
RFID is reading the data successfully.
Now let's just authenticate another block.
Block five.
And let's just read this.
Destroying all the zeros.
And we will write some data on block five as well.
We will use SRC format.
And this is my message one.
This is the data we will write on block number five.
To write binary block success.
Now, let's just read this data as well.
So it's reading in hexadecimal.
Now let's just read it in as well.
So this is my message.
So this is how you write data blocks in Mifare classic cards.
In the next video, we are going to see how we can update key A and key B, So in the next video, we
are also going to see how to update sector trailer and how to change the access bits as well.
Then we will see how to create value.
Block So we are going to see all this in our coming videos.